### Domenico Anastasio

## Web developer

#### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Commercial experiance
- Programming client-side
- Programming server-side
- Graphic design
- Responsive design
- Linux
- Adobe suite
- Search Engine Optimisation
- E-commerce
- S.E.O.
- Git
- WordPress

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

- Time management
- Goals orientated
- Creativity
- Attention to detail
- Teamworker

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

Domenico Anastasio

18 Suffolk Rd. London N15 5RN

Nationality *Italian* 

Mobile
+44 (0) 7932 902473
Email
nico@anastasionico.uk
Website
www.anastasionico.uk
LinkedIn
www.linkedin.com/in/anasta
sionico
GitHub
qithub.com/anastasionico

#### PERSONAL SUMMARY

A professional and determined person who always delivers permanently high standards, having a willingness to handle various responsibilities and get to know new environments and new technologies.

Able to independently organize work, even in stressful situations, thanks to the capacity obtained in relationship management with colleagues and clients during different work experiences.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Imperial Commercials Ltd | Travellers Ln, Welham Green, Hatfield AL9

PHP Developer | From January 2017

Employing PHP framework for create web application used by the employees of the Imperial group as owner of S&B Commercials and Orwell Truck and external web projects for the companies partners Duties:

- Implementing internal web applications for employees
- S.E.O. and Design of the official websites of the complanies
- Working alongside with the marketing department to accomplish common business goals
- Creating websites for truck dealers partners all over the UK territory

#### F.I.P.E. Web Design | 46 / 48 East Smithfield London E1W 1AW

Web Developer | June 2016 - September 2016 (Internship)

Realization of several projects from the research and design phases to the testing and launch stages, mainly using technologies such as JavaScript, OOP PHP and Smarty.

#### **Duties:**

- Detecting customer needs and realization of sketches and mock-ups.
- Making layout following the responsive standards.
- Implementing of bespoke scripts.
- Controlling of the language standards, cross browser testing and HTML + CSS validation.

#### Squadra Web | Catania (CT)

Back-end Developer | August 2014 – March 2015

Working with server-side languages like PHP5 and MySql, being in charge of the realization of back-end from scratch and implementation of the datebase into the front-end. Duties:

- Developing back-end, advanced database driven systems including ecommerce and mantenance of websites.
- Applying oncode Seo techniques.
- Liaising with clients and ensuring that all work accomplished complies with standards required.

#### City Hall, Office of Public Relations | St. A. Li Battiati (CT)

Front-end Developer | December 2012 - April 2013

Creating institutional websites for companies associated with the municipality of St. A. Li Battiati contributing to the development of the PHP scripts, planning the layout with HTML and CSS and realization of the graphic items with Adobe Photoshop. Duties:

- Designing layout from scratch.
- Writing server-side scripts and connection to databases.
- Realization of graphic and textual contents.

#### Maretna | Aci Bonaccorsi (CT)

Graphic designer | January 2013 – February 2013 Responsible to the pagination of the magazine using the Adobe suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign). Duties:

• Creating sketch and layout for print and online version.

#### **KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES**

Operative systems

Microsoft Windows; Linux CLI, GUI; Apple MacOS.

Front end

Html5, Css3, Javascript, Jquery, Json, Ajax, Bootstrap, Web design concept, Responsive design.

Back end

Php (Codeigniter3.x), MySali.

• General Knowledge

Linux (Cli, Gui), S.E.O., Git, Github, Adobe Photoshop. Adobe Experience Design, WordPress.

#### **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

• Search Engine Optimization (SEO) Marketing | 45 Moorfields, EC2Y 9AE

March 2017

Online payments

Understanding the key attributes of SEO,Best practice methodologies and strategic skills, manage online brands.

 WordPress Courses London | 22 Upper Ground, SE1 9PD November 2016

WordPress fundamentals, plugins and security, Google Analytics,

• CFP San Giovanni Apostolo | Catania (CT) 2012 – 2013

Web development, fundamental of web design.

• Technical Institute "Galileo Ferraris" | Acireale (CT) 2002 – 2007

Diploma in Computer Science - Project ABACUS.

REFERENCES – Available on request.